we really emphasize the ways in which
strategies and ongoing iterative process
that it is an incense essential part of
what you do as a leader whether you
think about what you're doing when
you're doing it as strategy or not
so you're doing strategy all the time
every time you make a decision because
of the most basic level strategy is just
about deciding how to allocate your
resources
so every time you make a decision about
whether to buys inputs from one supplier
or another or whether to you know invest
in this facility or to do this marketing
plan
you're doing strategy and in our
fundamental view is it's better to do
that self-consciously and to be aware
that you're doing it and to not be aware
of it and so I think we oftentimes kind
of could benefit from demystifying what
strategy is and just realize that a lot
of us in a lot of different managerial
and leadership roles are doing strategy
all the time and it's better to be
self-reflective about it than to be
doing it blindly
a strong leader is somebody who who was
almost able to think like a scientist
who's constantly able to move back and
forth between the kind of the conceptual
model or the the theory of the way they
think the world works and the reality
that they're encountering and then
they're able to translate the
experiences that were having or that
you're having as a group into a sensible
way of thinking about the world that the
rest of the group can really get on
board with and I think so really what
leaders do is they kind of build a
community right that the responsibility
of a leader is to think about the group
as a whole in the social group that
they're operating in a manager is
usually more concerned with kind of
technical aspects of of getting the job
done so how do I build kind of the most
efficient process but people also need a
sense of belonging and they need a sense
of kind of community in a sense of
purpose and I think that's really what
the leaders goal is
you have a plan that you want to execute
and part of your job as Gigi leader is
really to turn that plan into coherent
action right and part of that is about
what investment decisions you make and
how you allocate your resources but a
lot of it is also about how you organize
your people and the way you structure
the incentives the way you structure
reporting relationships how much
attention you pay to the culture what
kind of culture that you want to have
and even at the level of things that we
think of as kind of HR like things like
recruiting and who it is you're going to
bring onto the team
those things are all incredibly
important because if you don't have the
alignment between the way you've set up
your organization and the strategy
you're trying to accomplish and kind of
the key assumptions in that strategy
you're not going to be successful
I think the core question and strategy
is about you know when you have an
innovation or when you have an idea and
you kind of see an opportunity there
the problem that a lot of innovators run
into is that they they focused almost
entirely on the nature of the
opportunity they really think about
while this product is really going to do
something different for people
that's not easy to do right it is very
hard to come up with great innovations
but actually the harder part in the
thing that we really emphasize in this
course is it's not enough to come up
with the innovation you also have to
come up with the plan for how you're
going to profit from that innovation and
that is oftentimes much more difficult
and part of that and involves really
recognizing what the obstacles are that
stand in your way
and those can be obstacles in terms of
powerful buyers or suppliers that can be
obstacles in terms of rivals or
potential entrants into the industry
how do you build a plan how do you build
a strategy that's going to allow you to
overcome those obstacles because
oftentimes you come to the table with
this great insight about an innovation
that's going to have value and there's a
lot of work and getting to that point
and we really hate to see the
the work that you've done up into that .
go to waste because you never figured
out how to actually capture the value
that you're generating so I think you
know when we think about leadership we
tend to to think about particular
individuals right so we think about
Gandhi or Martin Luther King or Steve
Jobs or kind of these great figures that
we kind of all kind of think of as role
models and and I think it's important to
learn lessons from people like that but
I think it's also important to remember
that you are who you are and that you
have your own personality that you bring
to the table and your own strengths and
your own weaknesses and that effective
leaders are ones who recognize what
their strengths are and recognize what
their weaknesses are and build their
leadership style around that and it's
really important to have alignment
between what your leadership style is
and the kind of organization that you
build and the kind of strategy that you
that you pursue
I think we too much too great of an
extent think about leaders as something
that is an eight
I think everybody has leadership
potential and it is something that they
can develop over time I think it can be
learned by turning to others and asking
them for kind of you know in depth and
and kind of brutally honest kind of
assessment of what what your strengths
and weaknesses are
I don't think there's any doubt though
that that everybody has the potential to
be a powerful leader in the right
situation and at the right time
yeah